Andrew Tran

andrewtran@salesforce.com | 517-896-2112

Website: http://andrewtran634.github.io | Github: https://github.com/andrewtran634

SUMMARY

Software Engineer with experience in full stack web development, integration and unit test development, and big data systems development. Effective team player that works well in Agile and Scrum based environments. Excited about all opportunities to learn new skills and strengthen existing ones.

SKILLS

Proficient: Java, C++, Python, Ruby, Kafka, Akka, Flask, Django, SQL, HTML5, CSS3, jQuery, JavaScript, Git, Agile Familiar: Scala, Cucumber, Node.js, Adobe Illustrator

EXPERIENCE

Salesforce San Francisco, CA

Associate Software Engineer

May 2017 - Present

- Developing early stages of Customer Resolution Engine team's big data pipeline and engine to resolve issues of scattered customer data across multiple Salesforce platforms.
- Implement features to ingest, process, and resolve disjunct data, and features to concurrently stream data through different components of the pipeline.

Salesforce Indianapolis, IN

Software Engineering Intern

May 2016 - Aug 2016

- Designed and built Ruby gem to house common internal tools for Salesforce Marketing Cloud's Quality Engineering Automation Team, particularly a logging tool to expedite and ease debugging across development
- Built out QE Automation Team's testing web application to help Software Engineers in Test track and visualize test duration metrics using Ruby, StatsD, and Instrumental.

Vertafore East Lansing, MI Software Operations Intern May 2015 - Aug 2015

- Analyzed database fix patterns and worked with development to find and fix root causes of bugs
 - Utilized SQL and Pentaho Report Designer and Data Integration to automate customer and business report generation
 - Developed scripts to detect the website downtime of Vertafore's partner, the National Insurance Producer Registry (NIPR). Service was pushed to the company's SolarWinds network monitoring dashboard

University of Michigan Advanced Research Computing Technology Services **HPC** Developer

Ann Arbor, MI Feb 2015 - April 2015

Updated and tested system bash scripts on the university's High Performance Computing cluster to automate compute node reboots in the event of unauthorized user processes and user overuse of allocated memory

Institute for Cyber Enabled Research (iCER), Michigan State University

East Lansing, MI

Research Intern/Assistant

Jun 2014 - Aug 2014

- Designed and ran Python and Bash scripts to test and record computing node speeds on MSU's High Performance Computer's infiniband network.
- Developed Python scripts to collect data from my tests and display data in histogram representation, also wrote scripts to analyze collected data and identify potentially slow or faulty nodes

EDUCATION

University of Michigan Ann Arbor, MI Dec 2016